englishtown.com 2019-05-24

# Privacy Policy | EF English Live

The security of your information is very important to us. Find out how we keep your details safe. 

Learn more

Effective Date: 2018-05-24

EF Language Learning Solutions Ltd (hereinafter referred to as "EF English Live" and/or "EF") has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this web site: http://englishlive.ef.com.

EF LLS Privacy Policy

_Our Commitment to Your Privacy_

EF Language Learning Solutions Ltd. (“ **EF LLS** ”) is committed to protecting the privacy of our potential and existing customers. The EF LLS privacy policy (the “ **Privacy Policy** ”) applies to all Personal Data (as defined below) processed by us, including Personal Data collected or submitted through our websites, mobile applications or through our official social media pages or through other channels online and offline as further described below (collectively the “ **EF Products** ”). 

If you cannot, or will not, provide us with the personal information we reasonably require, we may be unable to provide you with the information, goods or services you have requested.  

EF LLS, Haldenstrasse 4, 6006 Lucerne, Switzerland is the controller for the processing of your personal data as set out in this Privacy Policy. Being the controller means that EF LLS is responsible for ensuring that your Personal Data is processed in compliance with applicable privacy and data protection legislation.

PERSONAL DATA

“ **Personal Data** ” is information or pieces of information that could allow you to be identified, such as for example:

  * Name and contact details (e.g. postal and email address, telephone number)
  * Account information (e.g. user name, profile picture or social media account ID)
  * Country of residence
  * Birth date
  * Technical information, e.g. screen/user name, IP address, browser and device data, information collected through cookies, pixel tags and other technologies, server log file data, app usage data and location data
  * Preferences (e.g. shopping habits, preferred educational courses)
  * Company name and address
  * Credit and debit card number  

**How do we collect Personal Data?**

We collect Personal Data in a variety of ways:

  * **Directly from you** :  Information is collected directly from you, either by you providing the information directly to us or you acting in a manner that provides us with the information, for example:
    * **Offline** :  We collect Personal Data from you offline, for example when you contact customer service, enrol in a product or service or provide information to us in writing.
    * **Online** :  We collect your Personal Data through the EF Products, for example when you sign up for a newsletter or a brochure, enrol in a product or service. We also collect Personal Data:
      * **Through cookies.** Cookies allow a web server to transfer data to a computer or device for recordkeeping and other purposes. If you do not want  
information collected through the use of cookies, there is a simple procedure in most browsers that allows you to decline the use of cookies. To learn more about cookies, please visit <http://www.allaboutcookies.org/>. For detailed information about the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them, please see our **cookie policy**. ** **
      * **Through your use of a mobile application.   **When you download and use one of our mobile applications, and to the extent allowed by your privacy settings in the application, we track and collect mobile application usage data, such as the date and time the mobile application on your device accessing our servers and what information and files have been downloaded to the mobile application based on your device number.
      * **Through your device.**   Provided that you have enabled that function on your device, we collect the physical location of it to provide you with personalized location-based services and content. Read more about such services under “How do we use Personal Data?”
      * **From our corporate affiliates, business partners, assistance providers or claim handlers**. We may receive Personal Data from other parties in conjunction with your course/program, including:
        * Our corporate affiliates, such as the local EF company that promotes the sales of our services and offers customer service in your country of residence and provides us with the Personal Data that is needed to come to an agreement with you on your order or provide you the services you have signed up for
      * **From other sources**.  We may receive your Personal Data from other sources, such as public databases; joint marketing partners such as marketing agencies or providers of software and services for digital marketing automation and analytics; social media platforms, including but not limited to; Facebook, Instagram, Snapchat, Musically, LinkedIn, Twitter, YouTube and messenger services such as WhatsApp or Facebook Messenger; from people with whom you are friends or otherwise connected with on social media platforms, as well as from other third parties. For example, if you elect to connect your social media account to your EF Products account, such personal data that you have registered in your profile, such as your email address, phone number, postal address, date of birth, name and user name will be shared with us. Furthermore, we use cookies to track members of social media networks as further explained in our **cookie policy**.
      * **If you browse our sites    
**We may also collect information about your use of our services through your browser to trace activity on our sites, such as your Media Access Control (MAC) address, computer type (Windows or Macintosh), screen resolution, operating system name and version, device manufacturer and model, language, Internet browser type and version, service provider, and the name and version of the EF Product you are using. In addition, an IP Address is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever you visit the EF English Live online school, along with the time of the visit and the page(s) that were visited. These data are only stored and used together with other Personal Data that you have submitted if you have given your consent to do so. You can read more about collection of your IP address and other browsing data in our **cookie policy**.  

**How do we use Personal Data?**

  * Your Personal Data will be processed by EF LLS for the purposes of providing you with the products and services that you have ordered, for customer service, administrative services or as otherwise necessary to perform the contract between you and us or as further described in this policy.
  * We may also use Personal Data:
    * For statistical purposes, calculating usage levels, and helping diagnose server problems with the EF Products as well as to ensure that the EF LLS Products function properly.
    * To allow you to contact and be contacted by other users through the EF Products, as permitted by the applicable product.
    * To allow you to participate on message boards, chat, profile pages and blogs and use other services enabling you to post information and materials.
    * If you have given your consent:
      * To analyse and improve our offers by identifying usage trends, determining the effectiveness of our promotional campaigns and tailoring the EF Products experience and content based on your past activities on the EF Products. For example, depending on what EF Product you have searched for on our website, or in previous browsing, the offer presented to you on the EF Products may be limited to a specific language, course length or budget.
      * To provide you with personalized location-based services and content through the use of your device’s physical location. For example, you will be redirected to the local EF website in your language if your device indicates that you are browsing from that country, or you may be suggested the nearest EF office to your location for visits or information.
      * To market our products and services, including special promotions based on your interests, for example through email marketing solutions such as Salesforce Marketing Cloud’s management software which maintains mailing lists and schedules and modifies email messages based on what recipients read, click-on or forward. All such email communication will include a clear unsubscribe link.  

**How do we share Personal Data?**

  * We may share your Personal Data with our corporate affiliates, business partners and service providers both within and outside the EEA/Switzerland:
    * Our corporate affiliates are for example a local EF company that promotes the sales of our services and offers customer service in your country of residence, or one of the principal companies that is offering another of EF’s program.
    * Service providers, such as providers of IT systems, for example for managing customer relations or payments, scheduling classes or storing learning results; or providers of software and services for digital marketing automation and analytics. 
  * We have put appropriate safeguards in place for transfers of your Personal Data outside the EEA/Switzerland, including the standard data protection clauses adopted by the European Commission, available at [http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32004D0915](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/EN/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32004D0915) and [http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX%3A32010D0087](http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087). For more information on standard data protection clauses in place, please see the contact section below. __
  * We also share Personal Data as we believe to be necessary: (a) under applicable law; (b) to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our terms and conditions or a contract; (e) to protect our operations or those of any of our affiliates; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our affiliates, you or others; and (g) to allow us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain.  

**On what do we base our right to collect and use Personal Data?**

We base our right to collect and use your Personal Data on the need to do so in order to provide you with the services or products that you have ordered from us, or when there is a legitimate interest for us (i.e. the service provider) to use your personal data, such as for the marketing of products or services similar to the one(s) you have already purchased from that same legal entity.  

**Please note that we ask you not to disclose any sensitive personal information on or through the site or otherwise to us.**

To the extent that we use your Personal Data to send you offers beyond what is considered to be within our legitimate interest, such as marketing of products and services provided by an EF affiliate, we base this on your specific consent.

SECURITY

We use appropriate organizational, technical and administrative measures to keep the Personal Data under our control accurate and up-to-date, as well as to protect the Personal Data against unauthorised or unlawful processing and the accidental loss, destruction or damage of the Personal Data.

COMMUNICATIONS FROM THE SITE

To send you an Email English lesson every day, we would, of course, need to know your email address. As an Email English subscriber, you will be added to our mailing list to receive occasional emails about service updates, special offers, and promotions from EF English Live and other companies within the EF group of companies.

You have the ability to unsubscribe from these emails at anytime, by simply clicking on the unsubscribe link included at the bottom of each email we send. 

We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email. 

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

UNSUBSCRIBE

If at any time you wish to stop receiving marketing communications from us you can use the unsubscribe feature in the marketing communication you received or let us know by using the contact information listed in the “Contact Us” section or by changing your privacy settings in the EF English Live online school. In your request, please indicate that you wish to stop receiving marketing communications from us.

Please note that changes may not be effective immediately. We will endeavour to comply with your request(s) as soon as reasonably practicable.

THIRD PARTY SITES

This Privacy Policy does not address, and we are not responsible for, the privacy, information or other practices of any third parties, including any third party operating any site to which the EF Product contain a link. The inclusion of a link on EF Products does not imply endorsement of the linked site by us or by our affiliates.  

Additionally, we may provide you with access to third-party functionality that permits you to share your activities on EF Products to your social media account(s), for example Facebook or LinkedIn. Please note that any information that you provide through the use of this functionality is governed by the applicable third party’s privacy policy, and not by this Privacy Policy. We have no control over, and shall not be responsible for, any third party’s use of information that you provide through use of this functionality.

HOW LONG DO WE STORE PERSONAL DATA?

We will only keep your Personal Data for five (5) years after the expiry of your account, in order to be able to provide you the possibility to re-activate your account, should you decide to purchase additional courses from us; or otherwise for as long as it is necessary for the purposes for which it has been collected or in accordance with time limits stipulated by law and market practice, unless further retention is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims or unless a specific time period has been communicated.

We will keep limited parts of your Personal Data which are necessary for marketing purposes until you withdraw your consent, but in no event for longer than 5 years after your last completed service or delivery of product.

IF YOU ARE UNDER THE AGE OF 16

If you are under the age of 16, you should review this text together with your parent or guardian to make sure you both understand them. We are not responsible for checking your age but sometimes we still do verification checks. If we learn that you are under the age of 16 and that we have collected information about you without consent from your parent or guardian, we will delete the information as soon as possible and you will not be able to use EF Products.

SENSITIVE DATA

We do not generally seek to collect any sensitive Personal Data. Sensitive Personal Data is data related to racial or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious or philosophical beliefs, health or medical condition, criminal background or trade union membership. In certain situations, this might however be necessary (for example in order to provide you with the services and products you have ordered). We will make sure that we receive your explicit consent to such processing and treat this information securely.

UPDATES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY

Our Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not significantly reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without informing you. We will post any Privacy Policy changes on this page and, prior to implementing such changes, we will provide a more prominent notice. Where required by law, we will seek your prior consent to any change.

YOUR RIGHTS

You have a right to, once per calendar year, contact us and without cost find out which information about you that is being used. You have a right to receive your personal data in a machine readable format and you have a right to transfer your personal to another data controller.  

You have the right to, at any time, withdraw your consent or object to us using your Personal Data for direct marketing purposes and you may at any time request that the use of your personal data is restricted or that we shall delete your personal data. Note however that a restriction or deletion could mean that we are not able to provide you with information, services or products as you have requested. Upon your request, we are also obliged to correct personal data about you that is incorrect, incomplete or misleading.

COOKIES

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that we store on your computer's browser or hard drive. We and our partners use cookies to remember personal information when you visit our website. For example, if you choose the view our site in French we will store that information in your cookie so we can show you our site in French the next time you visit. We also use them to store your login ID to make it easier for you to login to our site. Most browsers allow you the option of preventing cookies from being stored on your computer, though doing so will cause you to lose many of the benefits of EF English Live.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time.

We use the service of a third party tracking utility company to track the behavior of visitors to our site. However, we do not have access to or control over their cookies. The information we collect through our third party tracking utility company is completely anonymous and is used to improve our services and marketing efforts.

As is true of most websites, we gather some information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type and language, Internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. We use this information to understand and analyze trends, to administer the site, to learn about user behavior on the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

CONTACT US

If you would like to have a copy of the information EF LLS holds about you; a copy of the standard data protection clauses or would like to exercise any of your rights, please contact us at the address EF Language Learning Solutions Ltd., Haldenstrasse 4, 6006 Lucerne, Switzerland or click **here**.  

If you have complaints about our handling of your Personal Data, you have a right to contact the supervisory authority in the country where you live.

Cookies 

We use cookies to provide you with a better service. Close this message if you're happy with this, or find out how to manage cookies.
